Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/nita-sachan-phd-8135201 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Business Strategy Start-ups Strategy

Certifications

Licensing Academy Certification in "Technology Commercialization and Intellectual Property"

Honors-Awards

Awarded Women in Science and Medicine (WISMAC) Award (2007)

Nominated for the American Association for Advancement of Science (AAAS)/Science Program for Excellence in Science by the Univ. of Texas Southwestern (UTSW) medical center

Univ. of Calif. Davis Licensing academy scholarship

Univ of Texas Southwestern medical center post-doctoral association travel awards (2005, 2006)

Publications

Calcineurin and its regulator, RCAN1, confer time-of-day changes in susceptibility of the heart to ischemia/reperfusion

Sustained hemodynamic stress disrupts normal circadian rhythms in calcineurin-dependent signalling and protein phosphorylation in the heart

Reactive oxygen species regulate alkaloid metabolism in undifferentiated N. tabacum cells

Congenital heart disease-causing Gata4 mutation displays functional deficits in vivo

N. Sachan, P. Kaipa, A. Nandkumar, C. Dhanaraj. "Oral Insulin: Managing Breakthrough Innovations at Biocon"

Nita Sachan, PhD

Head Strategy and Solutions, Medical Technology and Healthcare (MT&H) at Cyient

Hyderabad

Summary

Nita has over 19+ years of experience working at the interface of business solutions, innovation and technology. Her expertise is in the areas of Medical Devices, Genomics, Biotech and Pharmaceuticals. At Cyient, Nita leads Strategy and Solutions at Cyient's Medical and Healthcare business unit. She helps drives the strategy for the business unit and new product innovation (solution) development through the internal new business accelerator (NBA). She also drives the healthcare-focused corporate venture investments, key account planning, channels, go-to-market planning and operational excellence. She also works extensively with the external ecosystem for enabling strategic partnerships with incubators, start-ups, firms, hospitals, government agencies, industry associations and foundations.

Nita is a deep believer in holistic solutions with a strong focus on business model innovation for increased technology adoption. Nita's expertise lies in-

- Innovation, Strategy and Business Development
- New Product and Solutions Development
- Key Account Planning, Channels and Go to Market Planning
- Design thinking and User Experience for solution development
- Corporate Venture Investments
- Technology and Business model innovation
- Due Diligence and Intellectual Property
- Mentoring Early Stage Start-ups
- Certified Licensing Professional for Technology Commercialization
- Contracts and Term sheets

Experience

Cylent

Head Strategy and Solutions, Medical Technology and Healthcare (MT&H)

September 2017 - Present (3 years)

Hyderabad Area, India

Medtronic
R&D Business Development
December 2016 - December 2017 (1 year 1 month)
Hyderabad Area, India

Mapmygenome - Wellness is in our DNA Vice President Strategy and Business Development 2014 - 2015 (1 year)

Indian School of Business 4 years

Associate Director at Business Incubator 2013 - 2014 (1 year)

Business Strategy and Development for the Incubation center.

Strategy, Innovation and Technology Commercialization 2010 - 2013 (3 years)

Univ. of California Davis Visiting Scholar 2012 - 2012 (less than a year) Davis, California

University of Texas Southwestern Medical Center at Dallas Postdoctoral Scientist-Dept. of Cardiology and Internal Medicine 2004 - August 2009 (5 years)

University of Kentucky Research Assistant 1997 - 2004 (7 years) Lexington, Kentucky Area

Education

Indian Institute of Technology, Roorkee Biotechnology

Indian School of Business Master of Business Administration (MBA), Strategy and Leadership

University of California, Davis Certified Licensing Professional, Licensing and Intellectual Property

University of Kentucky Ph.D.